RG 004:121, Salem Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Salem Probate Court records
1834-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Salem District)
10.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1842-1976; Probate files, 1834-1956.
RG004_121
1912-008 and 2014-009
Historical Note
Salem, New London County, Town established in May 1819, Parent Towns: Colchester, Lyme, and Montville
The Salem Probate District was constituted on July 9, 1841 from the Colchester and New London Probate Districts. The Salem Probate District merged with the East Lyme, Montville, and Old Lyme Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region #32 Probate District which serves the municipalities of East Lyme, Montville, Old Lyme, and Salem.
Town of Salem, Probate District chronology:
May 1819 - June 1824, No assigned probate district covered the part of town taken from Motville
May 1819 - May 1832, East Haddam District (covered the part of Salem taken from Colchester)
May 1819 - July 8, 1841, New London District (covered the part of Salem taken from New London)
May 1819 - July 8, 1841, Colchester District (covered the part of Salem taken from Colchester)
July 9, 1841 - January 4, 2011, Salem District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region # 32 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1842-1976. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1834-1956. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1834-1956 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2014-009 are numbered 1 to 11.
Probate files in accession 1912-008 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1912-008 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Salem
Places:
Salem (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2014-009, Record books, 1842-1976, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED pending review by State Archives staff as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-5, 1842-196, probate files, 1834-1880; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1912-008 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): July 23, 1912 (1834-1898); August 5, 1916 (1842-1875); October 23, 1937 (1879-1926); December 13, 1938 (1886-1938); January 4, 1946 (1922-1944); August 30, 1949 (1936-1949); December 30, 1952 (1946-1952); May 8, 1961 (1887-1956). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2014-009 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on July 22, 2013.
Container List
- Record books, 1842-1976; 6 cubic feet (11 volumes); 2014-009
  - Records, 1842-1872 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1872-1885 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1885-1886 (Volume 3)
  - Orders and decrees, 1895-1929 (Volume 4)
  - Wills, inventories, returns, etc., 1895-1916 (Volume 5)
  - Bonds, 1904-1976 (Volume 6)
  - Wills, inventories, returns, etc., 1916-1934 (Volume 7)
  - Wills, inventories, returns, etc., 1934-1945 (Volume 8)
  - Wills, inventories, returns, etc., 1945-1958 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1957-1970 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1970-1976 (Volume 11)
- Probate files, 1834-1956; 5 cubic feet; 1911-009
  - Allen - Bennett (Drawer 1)
  - Bliven - Chapman (Drawer 2)
  - Cherrick - Deroche (Drawer 3)
  - Dewolf - Fiumaro (Drawer 4)
  - Florko - Gates (Drawer 5)
  - Gifford - Hatt (Drawer 6)
  - Heilwell - Lane (Drawer 7)
  - Lang - Miner, D. (Drawer 8)
  - Miner, E. - Pattevan (Drawer 9)
  - Peltz - Rix (Drawer 10)
  - Rogers - Simpson (Drawer 11)
  - Siskind - Tew (Drawer 12)
  - Thomas - Way (Drawer 13)
  - Wetmore - Zeleznicky; Miscellaneous (Drawer 14)
- Inventory Control Book, 1834-1956; T003073
  Index of the eight accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1912-008
  Also known as the Godard Digest